Time is the enemy.
1917 is a war, history, drama film directed by Sam Mendes.
At the height of the First World War, two young British soldiers must cross enemy territory
and deliver a message that will stop a deadly attack on hundreds of soldiers.
Lance Corporal Schofield, played by George MacKay.
Lance Corporal Blake, played by Dean-Charles Chapman.
Captain Smith, played by Mark Strong.
Lieutenant Leslie, played by Andrew Scott.
Lieutenant Blake, played by Richard Madden.
Lauri, played by Claire Duburcq.
1917 is a 2019 British war film directed and produced by Sam
Mendes, who co-wrote it with Krysty Wilson-Cairns.
It is partially inspired by stories told to Mendes by his paternal
grandfather Alfred about his service during World War I.
The film takes place after the German retreat to the Hindenburg Line during Operation Alberich, and follows two
British soldiers in their mission to deliver an important message to call off a doomed offensive attack.
The two main roles are played by George MacKay and Dean-Charles Chapman.
Mark Strong, Andrew Scott, Richard Madden, Claire Duburcq, Colin Firth, Adrian
Scarborough, and Benedict Cumberbatch also star in supporting roles.
The project was announced in June 2018, with MacKay and Chapman signing on in
October and the rest of the cast joining the following March.
Filming took place from April to June 2019 in the UK, with cinematographer Roger Deakins and editor
Lee Smith using long takes to have the entire film appear as two continuous shots.
1917 premiered in the UK on 4 December 2019 and was released theatrically in the United States on 25
December by Universal Pictures and in the United Kingdom on 10 January 2020 by Entertainment One.
It was a critical and box office success, grossing over $446 million worldwide.
The film received numerous accolades including ten nominations at the 92nd Academy Awards, for which
it won three, for Best Cinematography, Best Sound Mixing, and Best Visual Effects.
The film explores themes of race against time, world
war i, british army, soldier, real time.
The tone is emotional.